Contact

484.889.7715 (Mobile) pscherle54@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/patscherle-5550a5a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing
Healthcare Management
Healthcare

Certifications

Nurse Executive Advanced- Board Certified

Pat Scherle

Vice President Patient Care Services|CNO at St. Mary's Regional Medical Center

Chester Springs, Pennsylvania

Summary

A transformational leader with extensive senior management experience in the healthcare industry. Impressive record improving organization effectiveness and client responsiveness. Talented strategic planner, including IT/IS, providing corporate direction for most cost effective performance. Outstanding people skills, a proven team builder and leader with a record of building client relations. Strong financial skills with the particular ability to manage budgets and control costs while maintaining optimum service levels. Considerable experience in facility planning and execution of such plans.

Specialties: Nursing, performance and process improvement, operations

Experience

St. Mary's Regional Medical Center
Vice President Patient Care Services|CNO
June 2020 - Present (2 months)
Lewiston, Maine, United States

Chester Springs
Actively seeking new opportunities
July 2019 - June 2020 (1 year)
Pennsylvania

Chestnut Hill Hospital Tower Health Vice President & Chief Nursing Officer October 2017 - June 2019 (1 year 9 months) Greater Philadelphia Area

Vice President & Chief Nurse Executive responsible for approximately 600 FTE's and the overall responsibility for patient care.

Specific accountabilities included administrative management of Nursing Services that includes Med/Surg, ICU, Telemetry, Perioperative Services, Emergency Department, Wound Care Center, Sleep Lab, Radiology, Women's Center, Laboratory Services, Education, Pharmacy, Physical Therapy, Senior Behavioral Health and Cardiopulmonary Services.

Responsible for the integration of nursing and patient care outcomes with other departments and services. The VP| CNO is a member of the administrative staff and collaborates with other Tower Health System executives in the organization, in decision making about health care service and organizational priorities. Plans and directs nursing services management activities for the delivery of safe and efficient quality care. The VP|CNO has the authority to speak on behalf of nursing and exercises final authority over those associated with providing nursing care, treatment and services.

Chestnut Hill Hospital
Chief Nursing Officer
October 2016 - June 2019 (2 years 9 months)
Philadelphia, Pa

The Chief Nursing Officer (CNO) is responsible for the integration of nursing with other departments and services. The CNO as a member of the administrative staff collaborates with other Community Health Systems (CHS) executives in the organization in decision making about health care service and organizational priorities. Plans and directs nursing services management activities for the delivery of safe and efficient quality care. The CNO has the authority to speak on behalf of nursing and exercises final authority over those associated with providing nursing care, treatment and services.

The Memorial Hospital of Salem County CNO

October 2009 - October 2016 (7 years 1 month)

The Chief Nursing Officer (CNO) is responsible for the integration of nursing with other departments and services. The CNO as a member of the administrative staff collaborates with other Community Health Systems (CHS) executives in the organization in decision making about health care service and organizational priorities. Plans and directs nursing services management activities for the delivery of safe and efficient quality care. The CNO has the authority to speak on behalf of nursing and exercises final authority over those associated with providing nursing care, treatment and services. The CNO

serves as the Facility Privacy Officer. Have also assumed the role of Facility Compliance Officer.

Cape Regional Medical Center Interim Vice President Patient Care Services October 2007 - May 2008 (8 months)

Chief Nurse Executive responsible for approximately 330 FTE's and the overall responsibility for patient care. Specific accountabilities included administrative management of Nursing Services, Wound Care, Infection Prevention/Employee Health and a Diabetes program fully maximizing a \$29.2 million operating budget.

Easton Hospital
Project CNO
August 2007 - October 2007 (3 months)

Primary responsibilities for nursing services and other projects as assigned.

Brandywine Hospital CNO August 2005 - August 2007 (2 years 1 month) Chief Nursing Officer

Chief Nurse executive responsible for approximately 300 FTE's staff and the overall responsibility for patient care

Specific accountabilities included administrative management of Nursing Services that includes medical, surgical, ICU, Progressive Care, Surgical Services, Emergency Department, and Joint Center.

Greater Southeast Community Hospital Vice President Patient Care Services/CNO October 2004 - June 2005 (9 months)

As Vice President, Patient Care Services/CNO and part of a turn around team, responsibilities included administrative responsibility for nursing throughout the system as well as development and implementation of clinical projects such as the development of the Wound Care Center, expansion of Behavioral Health, the Education Department and the development of a Women's Services product line as well as participating in the strategic short- and long-range planning.

Shore Health System Vice President Patient Care Services/Operations September 2000 - September 2003 (3 years 1 month)

Chief Nurse executive responsible for over 700 FTE's staff and the overall aegis of patient care for the system.

Specific accountabilities included administrative management of Nursing Services, Cancer Program, Pharmacy, Cardiopulmonary/Neurodiagnostics, Radiology, and Professional Practice Development, fully maximizing a \$52.5 million operating budget.

Education

Drexel University

DNP, Doctor of Nursing Practice · (2014 - 2016)

Villanova University

Post Graduate Certificate, Nursing Administration · (1999 - 2000)

Widener University

MHA, Healthcare Administration · (1994 - 1999)

Widener University

BSN, Nursing · (1989 - 1994)

Gloucester County Community College

AAS, Nursing · (1972 - 1974)